(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-12T22:58:39.610564",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
ご来場のお客様へ
Notice to Attendees
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
ご来場のお客様へ
Notice to Attendees
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください / 声出し応援 OK です
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance. / Cheering loudly is OK.
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援OKです
Cheering aloud is permitted.
Sponsor 協賛
[Sponsors]
あ、こっちこっちこっち！
Ah, over here, over here!
今日２人じゃないんすね？
So it's not just the two of you today?
え？２人？
Huh? Two of us?
さっきの。ここで会った人たち。
Those people from earlier that you met here.
心で...
In my heart...
Joyにいこうぜ！ JOYSOUND X1
Let's Joy! JOYSOUND X1
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
ご来場のお客様へ
Notice to Attendees
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援 OK です
Cheering loudly is OK.
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
本日は
Today,
猫又おかゆ 2nd Live
for coming to Nekomata Okayu 2nd Live
『パルソニアリスペクト』にご来場いただき
"Personearispect"...
ありがとうございます！
thank you so much!
めっちゃ盛り上がってくれてるじゃん
You guys are getting so hyped up!
え、みんな、1たす1は？
Hey everyone, what's 1 plus 1?
いいね、今日ラグないね
Nice! There's no lag today!
はい、もぐもぐおかゆです。こんばんはー！
Alright, I'm Mogumogu Okayu. Good evening!
こんばんはー！
Good evening!
最後までライブを楽しんでいただくために
To help you enjoy the concert until the very end,
いくつかご案内させていただきます。
I have a few announcements to make.
公演中の撮影、録音
Photographing and recording audio during the show,
録画機材の使用は固くお断りいたします。
as well as using video recording equipment, are strictly prohibited.
館内は禁煙となっております。
Smoking is prohibited inside the venue.
喫煙はご遠慮ください。
Please refrain from smoking.
万が一、具合が悪くなってしまった場合は
If you happen to feel unwell,
無理をせず近くのスタッフへお知らせください。
please don't push yourself and notify nearby staff.
会場内でのモッシュ、ダイブ、ステージにものを投げ込むなど
Mosh pits, diving, throwing objects onto the stage,
他のみんなに迷惑になったり、公演を妨げる行為は一切禁止です。
or any behavior that disrupts the show is strictly forbidden.
ルールを守って盛り上がってくださいね！
Please follow the rules and have a great time!
また、本公演は
Also, for this performance,
映像配信および写真撮影用のカメラが会場内に入り
cameras for streaming and photography are in the venue,
客席が映り込む場合があります。
and the audience may be captured on camera.
これらの映像や写真はプロモーションなどに使用される可能性がありますので
These videos and photos may be used for promotional purposes,
あらかじめご了承ください。
so please keep that in mind in advance.
ここまでの影ナレ、
For this pre-show announcement...
実はふりがなをね、つけてもらったので
They actually added furigana for me,
スラスラ読めてるでしょ？
so I was able to read it smoothly, right?
あ！
Ah!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
また、ライブのハッシュタグは #おかゆセカンド です。
Also, the concert hashtag is #OkayuSecond.
ハッシュタグを使って、たくさん盛り上げてくれると嬉しいな！
I'd be super happy if you use it to hype things up!
お願いします！
Please do!
それでは、開演までもう少しです。
Now then, there's just a little bit left until start time.
待ちに待った声出しありのセカンドライブ！
The long-awaited 2nd Live where shouting is allowed!
おにぎりやの声がいっぱい聞かせてねー！
Let me hear plenty of voices from Onigirya!
全然いらないじゃんか
You don't need it at all, do you?
わかってくれないじゃんか
You don't understand me at all, do you?
まあ仕方ないなって 思惑はしないけど
Though I don't really think "Oh well, it can't be helped."
全然笑えないじゃんか
It's not funny at all, is it?
面白くなりもしないじゃんか
It doesn't get interesting either, does it?
あーこんなもんかって
Ah, is that all it is?
よかれは期待か
Was acting for the best just expectation?
そもそもの話 君のこととか
To begin with, things like you
求めてることとか 分からないや
or what you're asking for, I just don't know.
泥々になる前に こんな感情
Before things get messy, this kind of feeling
やけどしちゃうくらい 熱々
is hot enough to burn. Hot, hot.
笑顔に甘えてるんじゃないの
Aren't you taking advantage of my smile?
優しさに溶かされてんじゃないの
Aren't you being melted by kindness?
答えが欲しいわけじゃなくて
It's not like I want an answer,
たまに思うだけ 気にしないで
I just think about it sometimes, don't mind me.
横須賀アリーナ！
Yokosuka Arena!
あっかんべーで忘れましょう
Let's stick out our tongues and forget,
世界はいらないのよ
we don't need the world.
いいよ いいよ 押し殺してあげちゃうわ
Fine, fine, I'll smother it for you.
あっかんべーで忘れたら
If you forget with a sticking-out tongue,
精一杯のドキドキしよう
let's feel the utmost excitement.
いいよ いいよ
Fine, fine.
もっと 振り回されたら開けましょう
More, if you're dragged around, let's open it up.
知りもしないくせに分かったフリ
Pretending to understand without even knowing,
それで好きだなんて面白いや
saying you like me after that is hilarious.
諦めの鼓動 裏で鳴るハロウ
Beats of resignation, a hello echoing behind,
混ざり合うハートは
the intertwining hearts are...
どこまでを許せばいいのかって
"How far should I forgive?"
ぐるぐる回る妄想は勝手
Spinning round and round, delusion is selfish.
頭の中を漂うループ
A loop floating inside my head,
毒かモードはどっち判定？
Is it poison or mode, which judgment?
ちぎれた僕食って大満足
Eating torn pieces of me and feeling fully satisfied,
腹を満たせやって言えないかな
can't you say "fill your stomach"?
ここにメインディッシュありますよ
Here is the main dish for you,
口すすいでおかわりはどうだい？
how about rinsing your mouth and having seconds?
あっかんべーの続きとか 思ったってやら無いのよ
Even if you think there's a continuation to sticking my tongue out, I won't do it.
だって...
Because...
虚しくなるだけだから
it only leaves me feeling empty.
あっかんべーをしたら 精一杯笑顔になれれば
If I stick out my tongue, if I can smile with all my might,
だって... だって...
Because... because...
そうさ 僕らは
that's right, we are...
あっかんべーで忘れましょう
Let's stick out our tongues and forget,
世界はいらないのよ
we don't need the world.
いいよ いいよ 押し殺してあげちゃうわ
Fine, fine, I'll smother it for you.
あっかんべーで忘れたら
If you forget with a sticking-out tongue,
精一杯のドキドキしよう
let's feel the utmost excitement.
いいよ いいよ
Fine, fine.
もっと 振り回されたら開けましょう
More, if you're dragged around, let's open it up.
ねぇねぇ びっくりしちゃった？
Hey, hey, were you surprised?
もしかして 怖くなっちゃった？
Did you perhaps get scared?
そう 全部なっちゃって 驚かせてごめんね
Yeah, it all became like this, sorry for scaring you.
ねぇねぇ びっくりしちゃった？
Hey, hey, were you surprised?
もしかして 怖くなっちゃった？
Did you perhaps get scared?
そう 全部なっちゃって どちらが僕でしょうか？
Yeah, it all became like this, which one is the real me?
僕の 深くて
Deep inside me,
君は言葉を待っていたんだ
you were waiting for words.
倒れないように
So that you won't fall down,
伸ばした
the extended...
願いに応えていくだけだよ
I'm just responding to the wish.
与えることしか出来ないよ
I can only give to you.
先は分からない
The future is unknown.
ほら 模様のように
Look, like a pattern,
僕の色彩じゃなくても
even if it's not my color,
素敵に着こなせるよ
I can wear it wonderfully.
君の視界の僕は 何の色に見えますか
What color do I look like in your sight?
張り巡らしたセンサーで 理由もなく好きになる
With sensors deployed all around, I fall for you for no reason.
しなやかな音届けるから 衣装を纏い待っていてくれ
I'll deliver a graceful sound, so wait for me dressed in your outfit.
風を引くまで
Until catching a cold,
濡れた顔に触れることが出来たらいいのに
I wish I could touch your wet face.
あたしの色は 誰かの言葉
My color exists to...
受け取るために 花を咲かせるの
...blossom a flower, so I can receive someone's words.
涙枯れたら 無限急行へ
When my tears dry up, onto the infinite express...
僕らは目を開いて口を開け 息をしないで色を飲む
We open our eyes and mouths, drinking colors without breathing.
君は僕から何か見える？
Can you see something in me?
って想像する心が欲しかった
I wanted a heart that imagines like that.
声を枯らすことのないように 僕にずっと色を付け足してね
So my voice won't go hoarse, keep adding color to me forever.
君の視界の僕は
The me in your sight,
君の世界の僕を どんな色に塗りますか
what color will you paint the me in your world?
季節にさらわれるまでは 理由もなく手を
Until being swept away by the season, reach out your hand for no reason...
涙を知りたいから 衣装を纏い五感をくれ
Because I want to know tears, wrap in your outfit and give me your five senses.
そばにいるほど映る僕で 飾ることが出来たらいいのに
I wish I could decorate myself with the me reflected as I get closer.
湿っぽい季節のデコレーション 咲かせるための依存関係
Decorating the damp season, a codependent relationship to bloom.
残しておいた余白で 君の感覚を
In the blank space left behind, fill it with your senses...
生の本音はエグいから ちゃんと火を通しておいてね
Raw true feelings are harsh, so make sure to cook them thoroughly.
リップサービスはズルいかな？ それも以心伝心のレシピ
Is lip service unfair? That's also part of the telepathic recipe.
みんな〜 自分偽ってるかい？
Everyone~ are you faking yourselves?
嘘の万国博覧会
A world fair of lies.
みんな〜 自分偽ってるかい？
Everyone~ are you faking yourselves?
痛みを飼いならしてシャー
Tame the pain and hiss!
嫌いだけど「スキ」 不味くても「オイシイ」
Hate it but call it "love", tastes bad but call it "delicious".
着ぐるみを着てハグしてあげる
I'll wear a costume and give you a hug.
泣かせないように 怒らせないように
So I won't make you cry, so I won't make you mad,
ちょうど良く君と遊びたいのだ
I just want to play with you in perfect harmony.
ネコカブリーナ
Neko Kaburi-Na!
猫かぶりな
Feign innocence!
ちょっと臆病な君が好き
I like you when you're a bit timid.
ネコカブリーナ
Neko Kaburi-Na!
猫かぶりな
Feign innocence!
取り繕ってる僕が好き？
Do you like me when I put on a front?
弱さを知ってる君が好きだよ
I like you who knows my weakness.
「思う」と「言う」とでは大違い
Thinking and saying are worlds apart.
建前も用法と用量次第
Surface politeness depends on dosage and usage.
みんな〜 自分疑ってるかい？
Everyone~ are you doubting yourselves?
ひとりぼっちの音楽隊
A lonely marching band.
みんな〜 自分疑ってるかい？
Everyone~ are you doubting yourselves?
首輪の鈴鳴らしてフギャー
Ringing the collar bell and meowing out!
災難だけど「ハッピー」 しんどくても「ヘイキ」
It's a disaster but call it "happy", exhausting but call it "fine",
アベコベな夢を見せてあげる
I'll show you a topsy-turvy dream.
傷つけないように 追い詰めないように
So I won't hurt you, so I won't corner you,
夜明けまで君とふざけあうのだ
we'll fool around together until dawn.
ネコカブリーナ
Neko Kaburi-Na!
猫かぶりな
Feign innocence!
爪を丸めてる君が好き
I like you when you retract your claws.
ネコカブリーナ
Neko Kaburi-Na!
猫かぶりな
Feign innocence!
涙を見せない僕が好き？
Do you like me when I don't show tears?
痛みを知ってる君が好きだよ
I like you who knows the pain.
もぐもぐおかゆ〜！
Mogu mogu Okayu~!
猫
Cat,
cat,
三日月の猫
crescent moon cat.
君は人
You are human,
人
human,
三日月の人
crescent moon human.
あれはUFO
That's a UFO,
UFO
三日月のUFO
crescent moon UFO.
君は猫
You are a cat,
猫
cat,
三日月の猫
crescent moon cat.
君は人
You are human,
人
human,
三日月の人
crescent moon human.
あれはUFO
That's a UFO,
UFO
三日月のUFO
crescent moon UFO.
君は誰
Who are you,
誰
who...
特別な人
A special person?
猫カブリナ 猫カブリナ
Feigning innocence, playing cute cat...
ちょっと臆病な君が好き
I like you when you're a little timid.
君も僕も馴染めない世界で
In a world where neither of us fit in,
やっと見つけた居場所だから
it's the place we finally found.
猫カブリナ 猫カブリナ
Feigning innocence, playing cute cat...
ひとりつくろってる僕が好き？
Do you like me putting up a front all by myself?
君も僕ももどかしてる世界で
In a world where we both feel so frustrated,
明日もまた会えたらいいな
I hope we can meet again tomorrow.
猫カブリナ 猫カブリナ
Feigning innocence, playing cute cat...
よさを知ってる君が好きだよ
I like you, who knows all the good in me.
3回目のモグモグー！
That's the third time saying "mogumogu"!
イエーイ！
Yay!
もうさ、影ナレも含めて3回もモグモグって言っちゃったよ。
Man, including the pre-show announcement, I've already said "mogumogu" three times!
このね、ライブの空気感でみんな僕が変なこと言っても「イエーイ」って言ってくれるからね。
In this live atmosphere, even if I say something silly, everyone just cheers "Yay!" for me.
これですよ。ということでね、やっとこの日が来ました。横浜ー！
That's what I'm talking about! So anyway, this day has finally come. Yokohama!
お邪魔しております。
Thank you for having me!
いや、もうさ、あっという間すぎたんだよ、この時間まで。
Man, time went by way too fast leading up to this moment!
さっきまで僕ね、お弁当食べてたんだけど。
Just a moment ago, I was eating a bento box, but...
え？食べるでしょ、お弁当！
What? Of course I'd eat a bento!
僕の食べたお弁当は何お弁当でしょうか？
What kind of bento do you think I ate?
もう何言ってるかよくわかんないけど。
I can't really tell what you guys are shouting, but...
え、ちなみにさ、ま、おにぎり屋だよって人、手挙げて！
By the way, those who thought "It's Onigiriya", raise your hand!
あー！最高！最高！見えてるよ、ありがとうね！
Ah! Awesome! Awesome! I can see you, thank you!
ヤッホー！
Yoo-hoo!
もちろんね、R席の配信チケットを見ているみんなも見えてるからね！
Of course, I can see everyone watching with stream tickets in section R too!
イエーイ！
Yay!
ということでですね、皆さん、なんとお気づきだと思いますが、本日のバンドは生演奏となっております！
So then, everyone, as I'm sure you've noticed, today's band performance is all live!
すごーい！
Amazing!
やっぱね、生演奏、お腹に来るよね、お腹に。
Live music really hits you right in the gut, doesn't it?
うわ、来る！お腹に来るぞー！
Whoa, it hits! It's hitting right in the gut!
僕のさっき食べたお弁当もたぶん「グッ」って、「ハッ」ってなってるわ、きっと。
The bento I ate earlier is probably going "Oof!" and "Gasp!" inside me right now!
えー、あとですね、残念なお知らせがございます。
Um, also, I have a sad announcement to make.
これ定番だよね。もう一回やりたい、もう一回やりたい。行くよ？
This is a classic, right? I want to do it again, I want to do it again. Ready?
ここで、残念なお知らせがあります！
At this point, I have a sad announcement to make!
なんと、冒頭無料チラ見せはこちらで終了です。
Believe it or not, the free preview at the start ends right here!
ごめんね。概要欄とか、あとYouTubeのチラ見せにはさ、固定してるコメントのところからチケット買えるので、ぜひお願いします。
Sorry! You can buy tickets from the description box or the pinned comment on the YouTube preview, so please check it out!
後悔はね、させません。約束いたしますので。はい！
I won't let you regret it. I promise you that. Yep!
配信で楽しんでる人は、ハッシュタグ「おかゆセカンド」でいっぱい呟いてくれると嬉しいです。
For everyone enjoying the stream, I'd be so happy if you post a lot using the hashtag #OkayuSecond!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
あとね、みんなさ、ポチポチポチポチペンライト変えてくれてたじゃん？
Also, everyone was clicking away changing your penlight colors, right?
実は、この僕のマイク...
Actually, this microphone of mine...
あ、離すと聞こえなくなるわ。
Ah, if I move it away, you can't hear me.
このマイクの色が実はね、ペンライトの色になっているから...
The color of this mic actually matches the penlight color, so...
何色にするかわかんない人は、このペンライト...
If you don't know what color to choose, this penlight...
色を参考にしてみてくださーい
Please try using the colors as a guide.
ま、遠くて見えづらい人は
Well, for those who are too far to see clearly...
あんまりね、大きい声じゃ言えないですけど
I shouldn't really say this out loud, but...
とりあえず紫にしとけば間違いないから
If you just set it to purple, you can't go wrong!
間違いありません、本当に！
You really can't go wrong, honestly!
と言うことで！
So with that said!
今日は、色んな表情の僕を楽しんでいってください！
Today, please enjoy all the different sides of me!
では、次の曲いきましょう！
Now then, let's move on to the next song!
無料パートは終了いたしました。ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The free preview has ended. Thank you for watching!
狂信者様へ
To my dear fanatic,
本日も心無い
today as well, I'm truly grateful
言葉をどうも有難うね
for your heartless words.
人畜無害な
Because you are so harmless
貴方様だから
to man and beast,
どんな能書きも
you get away with saying
許せちゃうのね
whatever pretext you like.